Noun Intonation Summary Rule 1 New Information Bob studies English. He
studies English. Rule A Descriptive Phrases Pretty good. A good shot. A pretty
good shot. Really long. A long talk. Really very long. fairly rubbery a rubber
hose a long rubber hose rule be compound nouns a snapshot a snapshot collection a
talk show a talk show host a rubber band a rubber band box a good snapshot a good
snapshot collection a funny talk show a
a cheap rubber band box, a really good snapshot, a really good snapshot
collection, a super funny talk show, a super funny talk show host, a very cheap
rubber band, a very cheap rubber band box. Rule C, descriptive phrases with sentence
balance. The Great Wall. The Great Wall of China. Seventeen. Seventeen dollars.
Seventeen dollars an hour. Seventeen dollars and ten cents an hour. Pretty
good. A pretty good shot. Fourteen. Fourteen years. Fourteen years old.
Fourteen and a half years old. Rule two. Old information. He studies it. Bob
studies it. Rule 3. Contrast. We need a red pen. We need a red pen, not a blue
one. Rule 4. Opinion. I should go jogging. I should go jogging. Pretty good. Pretty
good. I think so. I think so. Rule 5, negation, can't. I can do it. I can't do
it. I can do it. I can't do it.